Bessie Zuckerman papers
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bessie Zuckerman papers
Bulk, 1917-1934
1870-1964
2274
UCLA Library Special Collections
3.8 linear ft. (2 document boxes, 5 flat boxes, and 1 oversize flat box)
Zuckerman, Bessie
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7670710
Biography/History
Bessie (Besse) Zuckerman (circa 1886-1968) was a prominent member of the community of music associations in Los Angeles between 1920 and 1940. She founded the Santa Monica Bay Music Association and served as its president. She also served as president of the Bay Cities Music Association, where among other accomplishments she worked to make concerts accessible to school children. In addition, Zuckerman was chairman of the Venice Community Sing and of the Local Convention Board for the California Federation of Music Clubs. In 1926, she accepted an invitation to serve on the Hollywood Bowl Association’s Music Committee, and in 1927 the Hollywood Bowl Audition Board extended an invitation to her. Zuckerman was also a member of the Opera Reading Club of Hollywood and the Santa Monica Bay Woman’s Club, and she organized musical events for the Union League Club of Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of material relating to Bessie Zuckerman, a prominent member of the community of music associations in Los Angeles between 1920 and 1940. Items include music scores, sheet music, performance programs, correspondence, photographs, ephemera, and publications. The collection also contains a small amount of material concerning the composer and performer Mana-Zucca, and California music and entertainment figure L. E. Behymer.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Subject files
Series 2. Correspondence
Series 3. Photographs
Series 4. Music
Series 5. Ephemera
Series 6. Publications.
Behymer, Lynden Ellsworth; Hollywood Bowl (Los Angeles, Calif.).; Mana-Zucca; Zuckerman, Bessie--Archives
Container List
- Series 1. Subject files., 1920-1958.
  - Mana-Zucca., 1920-1940. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains photographs, inscribed scores, correspondence, and newspaper clippings from and concerning the composer and performer Mana-Zucca (Augusta Zuckerman Cassel, 1885-1981).
  - Hollywood Bowl., 1926-1958. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains programs, publications, clippings, and correspondence relating to Bessie Zuckerman’s involvement with the foundation of the Hollywood Bowl.
  - L. E. Behymer., 1928-1947. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Photos, correspondence, inscribed scores, newspaper clippings and publications concerning L. E. Behymer (Lynden Ellison Behymer, 1862-1947)’s role as a music and entertainment figure in California.
- Series 2. Correspondence., 1922-1930. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Content
  Primarily personal correspondence; also includes blank stationary for various music associations.
- Series 3. Photographs., circa 1920-1930. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photographs include inscribed portraits, stills from performances, and images of galas and events in Los Angeles.
- Series 4. Music., 1870-1964.
  - Piano and instrumental ensemble scores., 1870-1930. (Box 3, Folders 1-4, Box 4, Folders 1-5, Box 5)
  - Vocal Scores in English., 1900-1964. (Box 2, Folders 5-7, Box 6, Folders 1-3)
  - Vocal Scores in German, French, Italian, and Russian., 1892-1952. (Box 6, Folder 4, Box 7, Folders 1-5)
  - Inscribed music., 1915-1928. (Box 3, Folder 5, Box 8, Folder 2)
    Inscriptions are on sheet music and scores from Nino Marcelli (1928), Francesco Ferullo (1928), Mrs. Thomas Allen Woodruff, Florence Howard (1917), Ward Stevens (1920) Edward Lebegott (1915), and Percy Grainger.
- Series 5. Ephemera., 1925-1940.
  Includes Zuckerman’s personal scrapbook, fliers, pamphlets, promotional material, menus, press releases, and newspaper clippings, primarily concerning music associations and events in the Los Angeles area.
  Also includes programs from theatre, music, dance, musical, and opera performances in the Los Angeles area, France, and Germany.
  - Ephemera., 1920-1940. (Box 1, Folder 6, Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Performance programs., 1915-1940. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases., 1934. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Pre-publication drafts of the "Eventful Days of Westways," January 25 through July 1, 1934.
  - Newspaper Clippings., 1927-1935. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Santa Monica Bay Music Association., 1925-1927. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Series 6. Publications., 1930-1958. (Box 2, Folders 1-4)
  Includes a book, record reviews, catalogs, magazines, and publications of the Bach Society and Beethoven Sonata Society.